We're working with our wide receivers right now and we're working on some patterns they can run to get themselves open and hopefully make a big play for your offense.
We're going to talk about the post route.
It's very similar to the slant route except we want to go a little deeper with it and more straight across as opposed to a 45 degree angle.
The quick slant route is to get us a quick pass in the middle to try to go behind the linebackers and pick up about 5 or 6 yards.
With a post route we want to pick up more like 10, 12 or 15 yards.
So, we want to go a little deeper.
We'll have our receiver push the defensive back off.
When he gets about 8 to 10 yards he'll head across the field and the quarterback will throw him more of a deep pattern and let him go get the ball.
Let's run it at full speed instead of the walk through (video demo).
One thing to make sure of in the post route is that you really push that defensive back and get him in the back peddle so they think you're going long.
Then, you'll break it off and go straight across the field and the quarterback will try to hit you with more of a deep route than the slant (video demo).
You can see he took more of a deep route and we picked up a lot more yardage than we would if we just ran a quick slant.
That's called a post route.